[Subtitles by danielsangeo]
Huh.
Wow.
I feel like the universe doesn't
know what to do with me,
so it's just puking me up from
one room to the next.
I don't know where I'm getting
this imagery exactly,
but it feels like my reward for
escaping one situation
where I could be stranded
forever and/or killed,
is to enter another room where I
face the exact same dilemma.
Seriously, for what I've been through
today, the next room should contain, like,
strippers and party balloons,
[machine gun fire]
champagne, something along those lines.
See, not gunshots.
Hey!
You dumb shits are finally
attacking the aliens!
That's...that's a big one.
Y'know what, I'm just going to get out
of your way and let you do your job;
I have total confidence in you.
Go Army!
Or Marines!
Or whatever you guys are.
Not you, God dammit!
Spontaneous alien combustion.
Works for me.
If I could blow people up with my mind,
I could solve all my
problems in like one day.
[gargantua roars]
Okay, maybe not all my problems,
but earthquakes were never
on the list until today.
Whoa, that was close!
Okay!  God!  I'll go another way!
Hm, I don't hear any more gunshots.
I lied.  I don't have confidence
in those soldiers.
I mean, it took them this long
just to figure out that me
and the other
scientists aren't the aliens.
I've heard jokes about military
intelligence before,
but I just thought they were exaggerations.
Wow, that looks hot.
I want some marshmallows.
[vortigaunts charging up]
What the hell are YOU looking at?!
I don't HAVE any marshmallows, and even
if I did, I wouldn't give any to you!
THEY'RE MINE!
EVERYTHING'S MINE!
[gargantua roars]
Well, this facility's not mine.
I thought I wanted it but now I don't.
Ah.
See, I had a plan for how to rise
up the corporate ladder, too.
We promote internally,
so I was going to kidnap the
wife of the company president,
then, as a list of demands, I'd say the
manager above me gets, I dunno, $50,000.
Uh, hold on.
So, then I let him sweat
it out for a few days,
release her,
and then, money or no money,
the manager's finished.
If he's not arrested, then no way
in hell's he's keeping his job
with guilt of association like that.
Eh, this isn't the right ammo.
But, who am I kidding?
This company's never going to recover.
I wasn't looking forward to
kidnapping anyway.
I wonder if this was
boarded up for a reason.
[grunting]
Heeeeeere's Johnny!
Hey, how did you get in here?
Are you drunk?
Oooh...
GUARD: Mister, if you
can get the power on,
GUARD: that train would take ya
straight to the surface.
Are you serious?
GUARD: I would try it myself,
Wha--where is it?
GUARD: but it's a long way down
to the generator room,
GUARD: and there are...
I want to get out of here!
GUARD: things... in the way.
So, does this switch do it?
What's the procedure here?
C'mon!  I'm ready to go!
Come on...
Yeah, okay, I'll take the ammo.
Yep, that thing's still scary.
C'mon, do any of these do anything?
Blood...God dammit....all right.
That thing has flamethrowers, doesn't it?
Why does it have flamethrowers?
Jesus Christ, I think that IS
a punch card slot.
Eh, I'm getting out of here;
that monster's scaring me,
and, uh, you...have your gun if
it gives you any trouble,
so, we're cool.
Later!
Take it easy.
Okay, I think he said that the
train needs power.
Power.
I need power.
I have the power to get the power.
Because...huh...
These things would
make cool lawn ornaments.
I wonder if I could find a
taxidermist that would--
[gargantua roars]
Rumble rubble...
rubble rumble.
Rubble rumble, rubble rumble.
[vortiguant charges up]
No, dammit!
I'm not calling you!
What?
Where did that come from?
It fell from the ceiling.
Oh.
Boy, you could stash some drugs in there.
Mm, I don't see any.
Maybe the aliens ate them.
Alien sale!
Prices are falling.
No, wait.  It's the aliens that
are falling.  The prices are--
No, I'm not sure that works.
Hmm.  Yeah, I think I could talk a
taxidermist into stuffing one of these.
Just tell them I don't know what it is.
I found it hunting.
I think it might be a weird kind of rabbit.
He might buy it.  I dunno.
I'm a good liar.
[vortigaunts charging up]
Shut up!
[explosion]
I don't want your opinion.
I wouldn't even be lying, really.
Because this is...sort of like hunting.
And I really don't know
what these things are.
Though I do know that they're not
rabbits.  I'd have to lie about that.
Oh. "894GH".
That tells me where I am about
as much as I already know.
Ah.  Y'know, I think these doors
ARE sealed for a reason.
Oh boy.  Yeah.
God, not on my suit!
I just plunged into water at
almost terminal velocity!
I don't need it getting
messed up again!
I'm still not crazy about the orange
color, but it's a good suit.
Oh, are these grenade rounds?
[gunshots]
What the fuck?!
FOR THE UMPTEENTH TIME,
I'M NOT AN ALIEN!
Un-fucking-believable.
And here I thought they
finally figured that out.
That's what I get for giving
people ANY credit.
I saw them shooting the aliens
and not me for once,
and I ASSUMED that the military finally
got it through their thick-ass skulls
which targets they're
supposed to shoot at!
But, no, no, no, no...
That's for smart people like me.
I know it's obvious I'm a genius,
but is everyone else really this stupid?
I don't know, but I do know how to
prove who's more dead between us.
[whistling sound]
[turret firing]
Ah ah, ah, ah!
[turret beeping]
Why?
No, not my suit!
[turret beeping]
THE SUIT DENTS WHEN YOU SHOOT
IT,
[turret beeping]
SO STOP SHOOTING IT!
I hate you all so much...
[turret beeping]
Well, I guess I'll wait
for this to die down...
[turret beeping]
Yep...